YESSICA CHANTAL RAMIREZ

chantal.ramirez.dev@gmail.com | (778)594 6165 | Kelowna, BC V1W 3W3

Summary

Creative, personable and experienced IT professional with background in several different areas of information technology. Thrives in a fast-paced environment, good team player with notable problem solving skills. Ready to take on new web development and related challenge.

Technology Summary

- HTML5, CSS3 and JavaScript
- JQuery
- PHP and MySql
- Bootstrap
- React Native

- Version Control Systems: Git
- Agile Software Development
- Microsoft Office
- Google Apps
- Hardware and Software Configuration

Experience

08/2023 - 12/2023

University of Colima Colima, Mexico

Web Developer at Planning Coordination

- Provided technical support for website users when necessary.
- Reviewed information and elements regularly on websites and pages for accuracy and functionality.
- Redesigned sites to enhance navigation and improve visual appeal.
- Developed and maintained websites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Jquery, MySql and PHP.

09/2021 - 12/2022

University of Colima México, Colima

Web Developer at Teaching Coordination

- Development of modules with JQuery, Php, MySql and Bootstrap in the e-docencia platform of the University of Colima
- Directed design, writing and production of page content to fulfill project demands and satisfy customer needs.
- Dashboard data development for the university community.

09/2021 - 12/2023

University of Colima

México, Colima

University Programming Teacher Hourly

- Hourly Teacher
- Programming fundamentals teacher at the faculty of Telematics

06/2021 - 11/2021

YouGuestHub

México, Colima

Full Stack Developer

- Full Stack developer, Part Time.
- Developed requirements for system modifications and new system installations with Javascript and basic C#.
- Programmed applications and tools using object-oriented languages with goals of code abstraction, stability and reuse.

11/2019 - 09/2021

Technical Support at Technology Integration

University of Colima

• Technical support of teachers and administrative staff of the University of Colima.

México, Colima	 Training for teachers in the use of technological tools for education in person and online.
	 Content creation for online courses in University platform.
	Maintenance of the technological tools for the classroom section of the department's web

02/2010 - 11/2019 University of Colima México, Colima

Technical Support Engineer in High School #18

- Technical support for administrative staff, teachers and students in high school #18 located in Campus Coquimatlan.
- Management and maintenance of computer equipment in the school's computer center
- Set up equipment for employee use, performing or properly installing cables, operating systems or software.

the department's web page.

Education and Training

05/2021 **Bootcamp** in React Native Mobile Developer

Colima, México BrigthCoders Academy

10/2020 Bootcamp in Full Stack Developer JS

Colima, México BEDU Academy

06/2020 Master of Science in Master in Education

México Ateneo Institute

07/2007 Bachelor of Science in Telematics Engineer

University of Colima México

Languages

Spanish English

WebSites and Social Links

- https://www.linkedin.com/in/chantalramirez/
- https://github.com/ChantalRamirez

Certifications

- Full Stack Developer JS
- Official Scrum Fundamentals Certification